adotube.com 2017-12-31

# Privacy - Exponential

We deliver advertisements from hundreds of Advertisers across a multitude of Digital Content Provider properties. When you visit one of these properties, our automated system collects “click stream data” related to your visit to the property. Click stream data can include information such as your IP address, device identifier, operating system, browser type and language, content or pages viewed, the date and time at which that content was viewed and any interaction with content and advertisements on those properties. Technologies used to collect this click stream data include cookies and Web beacons.

We sometimes also augment this click stream data with behavioral and demographic data from Digital Content Providers and other partners. This data may include such things as postal code, age and gender. It may also include GPS location provided by Digital Content Providers with mobile properties. We require any third parties we work with to respect all applicable laws and the same self-regulatory principles that we do.

We do not use, store or collect information such as name, email address, telephone number or postal address.

The purpose of any data collection is straightforward – to show the most relevant advertisement to a user. We therefore utilize the information described above to better customize the sort of advertisements you see, typically by building models based on the types of user who, overall, are more likely to respond to a particular advertisement versus another.

We also use the data for non-targeting reasons such as frequency capping, fraud prevention, reporting statistics and billing, within the permissions of the NAI/DAA Principles and EDAA Framework.

Our tracking cookies are programmed to expire in ninety days from the last time we encounter you, at which point the web browser will delete them automatically.

Click stream data is stored in log files, which are retained in our systems for 24 months for billing purposes, and are not used for targeting.

We do not disclose unencrypted cookie id information to third parties. We only disclose IP address information if required for troubleshooting, and only then without other identifying information.

We enable consumer choice and control over our third party tracking cookie, which enables us to provide relevant advertising via behavioural targeting on desktop and mobile web browsers. In Europe, we require Advertisers and Digital Content Providers with whom we work to include this cookie within their legally-required cookie consent mechanisms.

Please note that the “opt-out” cookie must remain on your computer in order for us to recognize you as an opt-out user. This means that if you use multiple computers or multiple browsers you will need to opt out of receiving cookies on each computer and for each browser. Also, if you change computers or delete cookies from your computer you will need to repeat this opt-out process.

For details of our other cookies, please contact [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com).

You may also adjust your computer’s web browser settings to refuse all cookies. However, please note that because cookies are widely used, disabling the use of cookies in your web browser may interfere with full use of various websites.

Exponential does not disclose the personal information of its customers to third parties beyond the aforementioned behavioral advertising. However, should this change in the future, Exponential will notify its customers and provide them with the option to opt-out.

#### Opting Out of Behavioral Advertising on Mobile Applications

Any data we collect from mobile applications originates from third parties and is covered in the agreement during app installation.

To opt out of receiving targeted advertising on mobile devices, please see up-to-date manufacturer information. At the time of this policy, Android devices include this under Settings>Google>Ads>Opt out of Interest Based Ads; iOS devices include this under Settings>General>Privacy>Limit Ad Tracking.

#### Accessing your Personal Data

You have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain personal information relating to you. Upon request, we will provide you with access to the personal information that we hold about you. You may also correct, amend, or delete the personal information we hold about you. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his query to the contact information provided below. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

Your right to access your personal information may be restricted in exceptional circumstances, including, but not limited to, when the burden or expense of providing this access would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question, or when the rights of persons other than you would be violated by the provision of such access. If we determine that your access should be restricted in a particular instance, we will provide you with an explanation of our determination and respond to any inquiries you may have.

The only data we retain which may be construed as personal data is a cookie id and IP address. If you wish to know what information we have related to your cookie id, please contact us at [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com). We do not retain accessible log information for more than 60 days.

Exponential follows generally accepted industry standards to protect against unauthorized access to, destruction or disclosure of data. This includes undertaking physical, electronic and management activities to protect data integrity, access and use. Any data that is stored on our servers is treated as confidential and is not made generally available to the public.

Our servers are protected by firewalls and are located in secure data facilities to further increase security. Please keep in mind, however, that despite these reasonable efforts to protect data on our servers no method of transmission over the Internet is guaranteed to be secure and therefore we shall not be liable for any breach of security by an outside party.

Exponential complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.  Exponential has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

Exponential’s accountability for personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Exponential remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third party agents or service providers that it engages to process the personal information on its behalf do so in a way that is inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless Exponential proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In the event that another company acquires all or substantially all of the assets of our business through a consolidation, merger, asset purchase or other transaction, we reserve the right to transfer all data that is in our possession or under our control to such acquiring party.

Exponential is sensitive to the issue of children’s privacy. Hence, our services are neither developed for, nor directed at, children. We don’t offer the targeting of advertising towards anyone under the age of 13.

Exponential allows advertisers to target users in certain health-related categories. A list of these categories may be found [here](http://exponential.com/company/healthcare-privacy-policy/ "Healthcare Privacy Policy").

At the time of writing, we do not take into account the setting of the Do Not Track field in browsers.

You may also provide us with personally identifiable information (such as your name, email address, physical address or telephone number) when you elect to contact us about this Privacy Policy or any other customer-service related matter. We will only utilize such personal information for the purpose of responding to your inquiry. However, we do reserve the right to retain an archival record of all such correspondence.

We reserve the right to disclose personally identifiable information you have disclosed to us in response to judicial process or court order or to provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation of matters related to public safety, as permitted by law.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy by posting an updated version on this page. The date on which the current Privacy Policy was posted will always be noted at the top of this page. Any change we make to our Privacy Policy will be made in compliance with applicable law.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Exponential commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Exponential via [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com) or using the mailing address below.

Exponential has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit [https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield) for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. Complaining parties may also, in absence of a resolution by Exponential and JAMS, seek to engage in binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Panel.

Any other complaints regarding our privacy practices, or related questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy should be directed to [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com) or mailed to:

5858 Horton St, Suite 300, Emeryville. CA 94608. USA. Attn: Legal Department.
